COREY COLBERT

17 Yupon Drive ~ Huntington, Texas 75949

H: (936) 422.3808 C: (936) 404.4602

cdcolbert10@gmail.com

Information Technology Specialist

Solid technical background combined with 20 years of experience in analyzing, testing and managing the design, development, documentation, maintenance and configuration management of a wide variety of databases, software systems, computer networks and telecommunications systems, including all aspects of implementation and performance tuning. Integrates business requirements with the latest technologies to deliver cost-effective solutions. Core competencies include:

- ♦ Secret Security Clearance
- Quality Assurance
- ♦ LAN/WAN Strategies
- ◆ Team Building/Leadership
- ♦ Sets Performance Standards
- ♦ Cisco Routers & Switches
- Project Management
- Network/IA Security
- ♦ Excellent People Skills

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Information Technology: An IT professional proven successful in the most demanding of operational environments. Resourceful and adaptable, exercising superb leadership and team playing skills. Career highlighted by increased responsibility and constant promotion.

- Designed and implemented integrated IT solutions in close collaboration with executive leadership, analyzing current systems and engineering innovative and appropriate solutions.
- Ensured communications support and services to include phone, IP, satellite communications and customer service for 20K+ personnel in Japan, Okinawa, Diego Garcia, Guam and Korea.
- Oversaw uninterrupted network operations for as many as 320 end-users; ensured that all trouble tickets were swiftly resolved with very few issues having to be escalated.
- Designed and implemented the Information Assurance (IA) Program for USS Stethem (DDG-63), passing two intensive Dept. of the Navy cyber security inspections.
- As Electronic Key Management System (EKMS) Manager oversaw 1.5K classified items.
- Ensured the issue, handling, tracking and disposal of classified items in accordance with National and DoD Communications Security (COMSEC) directives.
- Provided regional and global communications support for Commander Seventh Fleet and its Asian and Pacific Areas of Operations.

Leadership & Supervision: A superior leader with demonstrated performance in high-pressure environments. Improved organizational performance through hands-on training and a leadership approach that emphasized decision-making through active listening.

- Superbly managed and motivated as many as 50+ personnel including subordinate supervisors; earned a reputation for firm, yet compassionate mentorship.
- Approachable, easily builds rapport with subordinates, peers and senior management.
- Developed topics and trained 300+ personnel in the handling of classified materials; developed other training programs for apprentice IT specialists; renowned for professional expertise.

<u>Problem-Solving & Analysis:</u> Consistently implements keen analytical abilities and a proven team-based work dynamic with a systems-oriented approach to facilitate efficient and effective solutions. A critical thinker open to alternative views to optimize decision-making.

- Planned and applied Command, Control, Communications, Computers & Intelligence (C4I) regional and global communications services for multiple U.S. Navy, Joint and NATO forces.
- Maintained 95%+ security compliance for classified and unclassified networks in accordance with Dept. of Defense and Dept. of the Navy-mandated IA and security directives.

Continued ...

EMPLOYMENT

U.S. NAVY, Various Duty Stations Globally

1996 - 2015

Information Assurance Manager, 2011 – 2015

Far East Watch Officer, Naval Computer & Telecommunications Station Far East, 2008 – 2011 IT Specialist, Commander U.S. Navy Europe / Commander Sixth Fleet Combined Staff, 2005 – 2008 Recruiter in Charge (Office Manager) / Canvasser, Navy Recruiting Station Victoria, 2002 – 2005 Communications Watch Officer (Supervisory), 2000 – 2002

Telecommunications Technician, Communications Watch Officer (Supervisory), 1996 – 2000

EDUCATION & TRAINING

EXCELSIOR COLLEGE, Albany, New York

Bachelor of Science, Business Administration, scheduled award 12/2015 Associate of Arts, 2008

<u>Certifications</u>: Security+ Certification, Computer Operator Department of Labor Apprenticeship Certification

Awarded the following U.S. Navy Rating & Navy Enlisted Classifications (NECs) concurrent with these equivalent civilian job descriptions as defined by the Occupational Information Network (ONET):

- IT Information Systems Technician
- NEC 2779 Information System Security Manager
- NEC 2782 Defense Message System Administrator
- Network and Computer Systems Administrators (ONET 15-1142.00)
- Information Security Analysts (ONET 15-1122.00)

Other Ratings & NECs: RM - Radiomen; 9585 - Navy Recruiter Canvasser

<u>Selected Military Training:</u> Shipboard Firefighting; Electronic Key Management System; Information Systems Security Manager; Defense Messaging System; Primary Leadership Development Program; Enlisted Navy Recruiting Orientation/Recruiter Canvasser (ENRO); Combat Lifesaver Course; First Line Leadership Development Program; DC Team Training; Radioman 21, Class A; Recruit Training

<u>Selected Awards:</u> Navy Achievement Medal (x3), Gold Wreath Recruiting Award (x14), Navy Good Conduct Medal (x5), Letter of Appreciation/Commendation (x6), National Defense Service Medal (x2), Overseas Service Ribbon (x15), Overseas Sea Service Ribbon (x10), Global War on Terrorism Expeditionary & Service Medals, Humanitarian Service Medal, Navy Unit Commendation, Armed Forces Expeditionary Medal (x2), Battle "E" Ribbon

Military: Information Systems Technician First Class (E-6), U.S. Navy (Retired)

REFERENCES

Excellent references furnished upon request.